Lowell Folklife Project collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
Lowell Folklife Project collection 1987-1988
AFC 1987/042
Archive of Folk Culture (Library of Congress), collector.
Lowell Historic Preservation Commission (U.S.), sponsor.
17,000 items; 10 containers; 4 linear feet.
158 folders.
90 sound cassettes: analog.
247 sound tape reels: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in.
ca. 13,500 photographs: b&w., col.
15 computer disks; 5 1/4 and 3 1/2 in.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
This year-long study conducted by the American Folklife Center yielded an ethnographic collection consisting of 196 hours of sound recordings covering a wide range of subjects and activities, including oral history interviews, religious services, musical events, parades and religious processions, ethnic festivals, ethnic restaurants, and neighborhood tours. An additional 23 hours of sound recordings of musical events and oral history interviews were copied from originals lent by Lowell residents. Collection materials also include correspondence; field notes; questionnaires; neighborhood maps; reports; publications; administrative files; interview transcripts; black-and-white photographic prints, contact sheets, and film negatives (ca. 10,000 images); and color slides and prints, (ca. 3,500 images) which documented community life in Lowell, Massachusetts from 1987 to 1988.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Bartis, Peter, 1949-2017; Bell, Michael Edward, 1943-; DeNatale, Douglas; Fertig, Barbara C., 1934-; Fleischhauer, Carl; Lueders-Booth, John, 1935-; Montaño, Mario; Norkunas, Martha K.; Rankin, Tom; Taylor, David Alan, 1951-; Wachs, Eleanor F.
Organizations
American Folklife Center; Archive of Folk Culture (Library of Congress); Lowell Historic Preservation Commission (U.S.); Lowell National Historical Park (Lowell, Mass.); Massachusetts Council on the Arts and Humanities.; Refugee Arts Group.; United States. National Park Service.; University of Lowell.
Subjects
Aguinaldos--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Baseball--Massachusetts--Lowell.; Boxing--Massachusetts--Lowell.; Buddhists--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Cambodian Americans--Marriage customs and rites.; Cambodian Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Catholics--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Christmas--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Churches--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Colombian Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Community life--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Dance--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Decimas--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Easter--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Embroidery--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Emigration and immigration.; Ethnic arts--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Ethnic neighborhoods--Massachusetts--Lowell--Maps.; Ethnic restaurants--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Ethnic schools--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Fados--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Festivals--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Fishing--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Folk music--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Folk songs, French--Massachusetts--Lowell.; Folk songs, Spanish--Massachusetts--Lowell.; Folklore--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Food habits--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Franco-Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Greek Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Holidays--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Hymns--Massachusetts--Lowell.; Irish Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Italian Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Jews--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Laotian Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Legends--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Music--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Musical instruments--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; New Year--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Occupations--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Orthodox Eastern Church members--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Parades--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Poetry.; Polish Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Portuguese Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Processions--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Puerto Ricans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.; Refugee camps.; Songs, Khmer--Massachusetts--Lowell.; Songs, Lao--Massachusetts--Lowell.; Songs, Vietnamese--Massachusetts--Lowell.; Sports--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Tales--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Textile industry--Massachusetts--Lowell--20th century.; Vietnamese Americans--Massachusetts--Lowell--Social life and customs.
Places
Lowell (Mass.)--Religious life and customs.; Lowell (Mass.)--Social life and customs.
Titles
Lowell Folklife Project; Lowell, Massachusetts Folklife Project
Form/Genre
Aguinaldos.; Correspondence.; Dance music.; Decimas.; Ethnography.; Fados.; Field recordings.; Hymns.; Interviews.; Oral histories.; Photographs.; Prayers.; Songs.; Sound recordings.
Arrangement
Organized by format into the following series: I. Print and Manuscript Materials; II. Computer Disks; III. Sound Recordings; IV. and Graphic Materials.
Acquisition
The collection was acquired in 1987-1988.
Access and Restrictions
Access restrictions apply; some or all content is stored offsite. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Existence of Copies
A reference copy of the collection was given to the Lowell Historic Preservation Commission, which intended to use it as the nucleus for a folklife archive at the Partick J. Mogan Cultural Center.
Administrative History
The Lowell Folklife Project was conducted in 1987-88 as a cooperative project of the American Folklife Center and the Lowell Historic Preservation Commission, with support from the Massachusetts Council on the Arts and Humanities. The Lowell Historic Preservation Commission, a federal agency charged with telling "the human story of the Industrial Revolution," invited the Center to develop and administer a cultural survey of contemporary ethnic and neighborhood life in Lowell in order to aid the Commission in its planning and programmatic functions, assist the State Heritage Park and National Historical Park in their interpretive programs, and create an archive of documentary materials.
Scope and Content
The Lowell Folklife Project yielded an ethnographic collection consisting of 196 hours of sound recordings covering a wide range of subjects and activities, including oral history interviews, religious services, musical events, parades and processions, and neighborhood tours. An additional 23 hours of sound recordings covering musical events and oral history interviews were copied from originals lent by Lowell residents. The photographic materials amassed by the project total approximately 10,000 black-and-white images and 3,500 color slides. In general, these images provide photographic coverage of events also documented on audiotape, but they also document occupational scenes, cultural artifacts, environmental details, and public events that were not conducive to sound recording. Print and manuscript materials amount to 6,750 pages and include fieldnotes, reports, and administrative material. Finally, 15 computer disks, which constitute electronic versions of the manuscript material, and an assortment of ephemera round out the collection.
The large body of information collected on the life and traditions of the people of Lowell served as the basis for "Report to the Lowell Historic Preservation Commission." The report discusses the project's course of development and implementation, briefly surveys the project holdings, reviews cultural issues involved in folklife research and programming in Lowell, and presents a number of recommendations for further research and public programming in Lowell. (A copy of the report is included in the collection).
Container List
- Series I: Manuscripts
  - Subseries I: Preliminaries
    - Finding Aid (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Preliminary Planning Meeting (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Proposal and Budget with related documents, 2 copies (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Research Plan (Box-folder 1/4)
      Drafts and final version, prepared by Douglas DeNatale.
    - Cultural Maps of Lowell and Project Proposal (Box-folder 1/5)
      Draft and completed version of grant application with related correspondence.
    - Agreement between Library of Congress and Lowell Historic Preservation Commission (Box-folder 1/6)
      Three drafts; original signed agreement; and related correspondence.
    - Lowell Cultural Plan (Box-folder 1/7)
      Invitation to unveiling of plan; two copies of published plan; and proposal for a cultural plan.
    - Lowell Historic Preservation Commission and Preservation Plan (Box-folder 1/8)
      Drafts and copy of final version of plan and LHPC Bulletin with item about plan.
    - Congressional hearing on Lowell Historic Preservation Commission Legislation (Box-folder 1/9)
      Testimony by Alan Jabbour; statement by Jabbour; copy of notice of passage of legislation in Congressional Record Daily Digest, July 21, 1987; description of hearing; and witness list.
    - Lowell Historic Preservation Commission Legislation (Box-folder 1/10)
      Copies of Act.
    - Massachusetts Council on the Arts and Humanities (Box-folder 1/11)
      Folk arts funding list; definitions and priorities for applicants in folklife and ethnic arts; publication on folklife and ethnic arts.
    - Patrick J. Mogan Cultural Center (Box-folder 1/12)
      Flyers and plan for immigrants exhibit.
    - Funding for Lowell Folklife Project (Box-folder 1/13)
      Schedule of collections; voucher for transfer of funds; fiscal reviews, related correspondence.
  - Subseries II: Administrative Materials (Box-folder 1/14-27)
    Contains contracts; invoices; job announcements; applications; vitae; correspondence; and list of contracted fieldworkers.
  - Subseries III: Correspondence
    - Bartis, Peter (Box-folder 1/28)
    - DeNatale, Douglas, 1987 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - DeNatale, Douglas, 1988 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Dockstader, Ray; D'Ooge, Craig; Fleischhauer, Carl; Hyde, Phil (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Informants (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Jabbour, Alan; Lueders-Booth, Jack; Marion, Paul (Box-folder 2/33)
    - Matchak, Steve; Rankin, Tom; Wachs, Eleanor (Box-folder 2/34)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/35)
    - Norkunas, Martha (Box-folder 2/36)
    - Taylor, David A. (Box-folder 2/37)
  - Subseries IV: Equipment, Services, and Supplies
    - Equipment: Computers and Software (Box-folder 2/38)
      Invoices; warranties; registration cards; catalog; manuals.
    - Equipment: Sound Recording Equipment (Box-folder 2/39)
      Manuals; draft of report "Operating the Stereo Nagra Tape Recorder for Folklife Fieldwork."
    - Equipment: Inventories (Box-folder 2/40)
      Lists of documentation equipment; notes.
    - Services (Box-folder 2/41)
      Invoices; purchase requisitions; related correspondence; brochures.
    - Supplies (Box-folder 2/42)
      Invoices; purchase orders; receipts for property; shipping records; list of supplies needed; packing list.
  - Subseries V: Contacts
    - Colleagues and Media (Box-folder 2/43)
    - Interview Leads (Box-folder 2/44)
      Business cards; notes; lists of contacts; National Folk Festival craft and demonstration fact sheets.
  - Subseries VI: Informants
    - Certificate of Appreciation (Box-folder 2/45)
      Copies of blank certificate
    - Blank forms (Box-folder 2/46)
      Copies of five types of informant consent forms.
    - Consent Forms - Signed (Box-folder 2/47)
      Informant consent forms of two types - (1) consent to place tapes and/or photos in public archive "where they will be available to researchers and the public for scholarly and educational purposes including publications and exhibitions," and (2) consent forms signed by the fieldworker stating that although the informant did not sign a consent form, he/she did agree to have materials placed in a research archive and consented to "allowing the interviewee's words to be quoted or pictures to be shown in a publication or exhibit."
    - Informant Addresses, circa 270 index cards (Box-folder 3/48)
    - James Campbell interview transcript (Box-folder 3/49)
      Interview with James Campbell by Bill (last name not given) for the University of Lowell, Center for Lowell History, Oral History Collection.
  - Subseries VII: Publicity and Public Relations
    - Lowell Folklife Project Announcement (Box-folder 3/50)
      Invitations; mailing lists; tentative agenda for announcement; list of speakers.
    - Lowell Folklife Project Briefing (Box-folder 3/51)
      Announcement of briefing; mailing lists.
    - Articles (Box-folder 3/52)
      Copies of newspaper and newsletter about the project.
    - Press Releases (Box-folder 3/53)
      Drafts and copies of final press release; mailing list.
    - Project Handouts (Box-folder 3/54)
      Copies of flyer and fieldworker business card.
    - Article from Festival of American Folklife Program Book (Box-folder 3/55)
      Draft of article; guidelines for Festival of American Folklife program book; notes; related correspondence.
  - Subseries VIII: Miscellaneous
    - Lowell Neighborhood Project (Box-folder 3/56)
      Progress Report: two copies.
    - Crafts Survey Outline by Eleanor Wachs (Box-folder 3/57)
      List of survey questions.
    - Brush with History Gallery - Exhibit (Box-folder 3/58)
      List of potential exhibit photographs; Library of Congress mail and freight record; brochure for exhibit "Sacred Spaces - The Spiritual in Folk Art."
    - AFC Board of Trustees Meeting in Lowell (Box-folder 3/59)
      Copy of minutes.
    - Lowell Conference on Industrial History (Box-folder 3/60)
      Brochure; list of speakers; call for papers; preliminary program; final program; list of registrants.
  - Subseries IX: Documentary Materials
    - Indices
      - Indexing Procedures (Box-folder 3/61)
        Memorandum from Carl Fleischhauer regarding index for project; drafts of "Notes on Archiving and Media Documentation," prepared by Carl Fleischhauer; memorandum from Marsha Maguire regarding subject and proper-name headings; draft of thesaurus prepared by Douglas DeNatale; "Introduction to XyWrite and to the `NEWLOG' and `INDEXER' Programs," prepared by Douglas DeNatale.
      - Name Index (Box-folder 3/62)
        pp. 30-63 are mislabeled as "Topical Index"
      - Topical Index (1 of 2) (Box-folder 3/63)
      - Topical Index (2 of 2) (Box-folder 3/64)
      - Index to Sound Recordings (Box-folder 3/65)
    - Audio Logs: Audiocassettes
      - Audiocassette logs - copies of loaned original recordings: LFP-CC-A001 through LFP-CC-A023. (Box-folder 4/66)
      - Bell, Michael: LFP-MB-A001 through LFP-MB-A005 (Box-folder 4/67)
      - DeNatale, Douglas: LFP-DD-A001 through LFP-DD-A005 (Box-folder 4/68)
      - Fertig, Barbara: LFP-BF-A001 through LFP-BF-A013 (Box-folder 4/69)
      - Montaño, Mario: LFP-MM-A001 through LFP-MM-A024 (Box-folder 4/70)
      - Rankin, Tom: LFP-TR-A001 through LFP-TR-A004 (Box-folder 4/71)
      - Refugee Arts Group: LFP-RA-A001 through LFP-RA-A015 (Box-folder 4/72)
      - Taylor, David: LFP-DT-A001 through LFP-DT-A002 (Box-folder 4/73)
      - Wach, Eleanor: LFP-EW-A001 through LFP-EW-A004 (Box-folder 4/74)
    - Audio Logs: Reel-to-reel tapes
      - Bell, Michael: LFP-MB-R001 through LFP-MB-R020 (Box-folder 4/75)
      - DeNatale, Douglas: LFP-DD-R001 through LFP-DD-R080 (Box-folder 4/76)
      - Fertig, Barbara: LFP-BF-R001 through LFP-BF-R002 (Box-folder 4/77)
      - Montaño, Mario: LFP-MM-R001 through LFP-MM-R016 (Box-folder 4/78)
      - Norkunas, Martha: LFP-MN-R001 through LFP-MN-R053 (Box-folder 4/79)
      - Rankin, Tom: LFP-TR-R001 through LFP-TR-R043 (Box-folder 4/80)
      - Taylor, David: LFP-DT-R001 through LFP-DT-R033 (Box-folder 4/81)
    - Transcripts of Sound Recordings (prepared by University of Lowell, Center for Lowell History, Oral History Collection)
      - Transcript of loaned original recording: transcript of LFP-CC-A023 (Box-folder 5/82)
      - Transcripts of interviews conducted by Michael Bell: transcripts of LFP-MB-R001 through LFP-MB-R005, LFP-MB-R008 through LFP-MB-R011, LFP-MB-R019 through LFP-MB-R020 (Box-folder 5/83)
      - Transcripts of interviews conducted by Douglas DeNatale: transcripts of LFP-DD-R070 through LFP-DD-R071 (Box-folder 5/84)
      - Transcript of interview conducted by Barbara Fertig: transcript of LFP-BF-A013 (Box-folder 5/85)
      - Transcript of interview conducted by Mario Montaño: transcript of LFP-MM-A011 (Box-folder 5/86)
      - Transcripts of interviews conducted by Martha Norkunas: transcripts of LFP-MN-R003 through LFP-MN-R007, LFP-MN-R016 through LFP-MN-R017, LFP-MN-R019 through LFP-MN-R020, LFP-MN-R048 through LFP-MN-R049 (Box-folder 5/87)
      - Transcripts of interviews conducted by Tom Rankin: transcripts of LFP-TR-A001, LFP-TR-R001 through LFP-TR-R002, LFP-TR-R022 through LFP-TR-R023 (Box-folder 5/88)
      - Transcripts of interviews conducted by David Taylor (1 of 2): transcripts of LFP-DT-A001, LFP-DT-R001 through LFP-DT-R002, LFP-DT-R007 through LFP-DT-R010, LFP-DT-R017 through LFP-DT-R019 (Box-folder 5/89)
      - Transcripts of interviews conducted by David Taylor (2 of 2): transcripts of LFP-DT-R023 through LFP-DT-R027 (Box-folder 5/90)
    - Fieldnotes
      - Bell, Michael (Box-folder 5/91)
      - Lueders-Booth, John (handwritten) (Box-folder 5/92)
      - Lueders-Booth, John (Box-folder 5/93)
      - DeNatale, Douglas (handwritten) (Box-folder 5/94)
      - DeNatale, Douglas (Box-folder 5/95)
      - Fertig, Barbara (Box-folder 6/96)
      - Fleischhauer, Carl (Box-folder 6/97)
      - Montaño, Mario (Box-folder 6/98)
      - Norkunas, Martha (handwritten) (Box-folder 6/99)
      - Norkunas, Martha (Box-folder 6/100)
      - Rankin, Tom (Box-folder 6/101)
      - Refugee Arts Group (Box-folder 6/102)
      - Taylor, David (Box-folder 6/103)
      - Wachs, Eleanor (handwritten) (Box-folder 6/104)
      - Wachs, Eleanor (Box-folder 6/105)
    - Black-and-White Photograph Logs
      - Bartis, Peter (Box-folder 6/106)
      - Bell, Michael (Box-folder 6/107)
      - Leuders-Booth, John (Box-folder 6/108)
      - DeNatale, Douglas (Box-folder 6/109)
      - Fertig, Barbara (Box-folder 6/110)
      - Fleischhauer, Carl (Box-folder 6/111)
      - Montaño, Mario (Box-folder 6/112)
      - Norkunas, Martha (Box-folder 6/113)
      - Rankin, Tom (Box-folder 6/114)
      - Taylor, David (Box-folder 6/115)
      - Wachs, Eleanor (Box-folder 6/116)
      - Numerical set: B001 through B199 (Box-folder 6/117)
      - Numerical set: B200 through B349 (Box-folder 7/118)
      - Numerical set: B350 through B487 (Box-folder 7/119)
    - Color-Slide Logs
      - Inventory of color photographic materials prepared for "phoney fiche" (index to all the color slides) shooting (Box-folder 7/120)
      - Bell, Michael: LFP-MB-C001 through LFP-MB-C004 (Box-folder 7/121)
      - Lueders-Booth, John: LFP-JB-C001 through LFP-JB-C081 (Box-folder 7/122)
      - DeNatale, Douglas: LFP-DD-C001 through LFP-DD-C040 (Box-folder 7/123)
      - Fertig, Barbara: LFP-BF-C001 (Box-folder 7/124)
      - Fleischhauer, Carl: LFP-CF-C001 through LFP-CF-C004 (Box-folder 7/125)
      - Montaño, Mario: LFP-MM-C001 through LFP-MM-C017 (Box-folder 7/126)
      - Norkunas, Martha: LFP-MN-C001 through LFP-MN-C013 (Box-folder 7/127)
      - Rankin, Tom: LFP-TR-C001 through LFP-TR-C098 (Box-folder 7/128)
      - Taylor, David: LFP-DT-C001 through LFP-DT-C017 (Box-folder 7/129)
      - Wachs, Eleanor: LFP-EW-C001 through LFP-EW-C002 (Box-folder 7/130)
    - Lowell Neighborhood Map Project (Box-folder 7/131)
      Map questionnaire form; related correspondence; completed questionnaires and maps; listing of Lowell streets and post offices.
    - Lowell Fishing and Swimming Spots (Box-folder 7/132)
      List and map of fishing and swimming spots, past and present.
    - Refugee Arts Group (Box-folder 7/133)
      Reports prepared by the Refugee Arts Group about the Vietnamese, Cambodian, and Laotian communities of Lowell; transcripts of interviews; lists of contacts.
  - Subseries X: Reports
    - Draft Outline of "Report to The Lowell Historic Preservation Commission" by Douglas DeNatale (Box-folder 8/134)
    - Drafts of "Report to The Lowell Historic Preservation Commission" by Douglas DeNatale (Box-folder 8/135)
    - Manuscript of "Report to The Lowell Historic Preservation Commission" by Douglas DeNatale (Box-folder 8/136)
    - "Report to The Lowell Historic Preservation Commission" by Douglas DeNatale (Box-folder 8/137)
    - Drafts of "Recommendations for Folklife Planning in Lowell" by Douglas DeNatale (Box-folder 8/138)
    - "Report to The Lowell Historic Preservation Commission: Planning Document on Folklife Initiative" by Douglas DeNatale (Box-folder 8/139)
  - Subseries XI: Publications and Ephemera
    - Folklife Curriculum Materials (Box-folder 8/140)
      "Introductory Bibliography for Folk Arts in Education" and "Understanding Folk Art: Forms For and From Everyone" by Janice Gadaire.
    - Guidebooks, Maps, and Brochures to Lowell Attractions (Box-folder 8/141)
    - Heinzelmann, Willy. Azores (Basel, Switzerland: Willy Heinzelmann, 1985) (Box-folder 8/142)
      Two guidebooks; maps of downtown Lowell and the National Historical Park; brochure on park activities; Lowell Line Commuter Rail schedules
    - Books (Box 10)
      - Higgins, James. Lowell: A Contemporary View (Lowell: Mill Town Graphics, 1983)
      - Higgins, James and Joan Ross. Southeast Asians: A New Beginning In Lowell (Lowell: Mill Town Graphics, 1986)
    - Recordings of Portuguese Music
      - Conjunto Da Cave - Camacheira Florista, Meus Tempos De Mocidade (Revere, MA: Fleetwood Records)
      - Henrique Cordeiro - California Como Tu Nao Ha Igual (Mountain View, CA: Marca H. F. Discos)
      - Cidalia Maria - Canta para os Imigrantes (Ludlow, MA: M & N Recordings)
    - Lowell Historic Preservation Commission - Miscellaneous Documents (Box-folder 8/143)
      1982 Annual Report; 1987 Newsletter; Details of the Preservation Plan
    - Lowell National Historical Park (Box-folder 8/144)
      Report of the Canalway Task Force; Institute for Urban Design monograph on Lowell National Park; copy of drawing of park area.
    - The Lowell Plan (Box-folder 8/145)
      Copy of plan; newsletter.
    - Map showing French and Irish settlements in Lowell in 1876 (Box-folder 8/146)
    - Marion, Paul. Strong Place -- Poems '74-'84 (Lowell: Loom Press, 1984) (Box-folder 8/147)
    - Medal from Saint Anthony's Church seventy-fifth anniversary (Box-folder 9/148)
    - National Folk Festival, Lowell (Box-folder 9/149)
      Festival pamphlet; press release
    - Newspaper and Magazine Articles about Lowell (Box-folder 9/150)
    - Nineteenth-Century Letters from Lowell "Mill Girl" (Box-folder 9/151)
      Copies of letters provided by informants Robert and Arleen Stykemain
    - Poem "Jimmy Allen at the Library of Congress," by Paul Marion (Box-folder 9/152)
    - Programs (Box-folder 9/153)